[
  {
    "correctOption": "The liturgy of the word",
    "firstOption": "The holy Eucharist",
    "question": "The psalm is read in what part of the mass?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Concluding rite",
    "thirdOption": "The liturgy of the word",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Mother Theresa",
    "firstOption": "St. Agnes",
    "question": "Who won the nobel peace prize for her work in india?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Mother Theresa",
    "thirdOption": "St. Monica",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Purgatory",
    "firstOption": "Heaven",
    "question": "Final purification will take place in?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Hell",
    "thirdOption": "Purgatory",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "1566",
    "firstOption": "The first century",
    "question": "The first official universal Catechism was published in?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "1899",
    "thirdOption": "1566",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Creed, Sacraments, Commandments, Prayer",
    "firstOption": " Creed, Sacraments, Commandments, Prayer",
    "question": "The “four pillars” of the Catechism are?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Eucharist, Commandments, Scripture, Church history",
    "thirdOption": "Sacraments, Commandments, Prayer, Scripture",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Eucharist",
    "firstOption": "Baptism",
    "question": "The “source and summit” of Christian life is?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Orders",
    "thirdOption": "Eucharist",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "24,000",
    "firstOption": "556",
    "question": "One draft of the Catechism submitted to the bishops of the world resulted in this many suggested changes?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "24,000",
    "thirdOption": "3,000",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Jesus Christ",
    "firstOption": "Jesus Christ",
    "question": "Who is the “physician of our souls and bodies”? ",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Holy Spirit",
    "thirdOption": "Mary",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Our Father",
    "firstOption": "Apostles’ Creed",
    "question": "The fourth “pillar” of the Catechism focuses at length on this prayer?",
    "quiz": "CatholicFaith",
    "secondOption": "Our Father",
    "thirdOption": "Rosary",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "14",
    "firstOption": "14",
    "question": "How many apostles did St. Paul have?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "13",
    "thirdOption": "12",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Jesus’ second coming",
    "firstOption": "Jesus’ second coming",
    "question": "“Parousia” refers to?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The gift of tongues",
    "thirdOption": "One of the seven gifts of the Holy Spirit",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Confirmation",
    "firstOption": "Baptism",
    "question": "“Be sealed with the gift of the Holy Spirit” is spoken during which sacrament?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Anointing of the Sick",
    "thirdOption": "Confirmation",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Code of Canon Law",
    "firstOption": "Code of Canon Law",
    "question": "Ecclesiastical Law refers to laws found in?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "New Testament",
    "thirdOption": "Old Testament",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Vatican City",
    "firstOption": "Vatican City",
    "question": "Where does the pope live?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Rome",
    "thirdOption": "Italy",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Lord have Mercy",
    "firstOption": "Lord have Mercy",
    "question": "Which part of the Latin mass is said in greek?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "I believe",
    "thirdOption": "Glory to God",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Individual Catholic families",
    "firstOption": "Individual Catholic families",
    "question": "When the Catechism refers to a “privileged community,” it means?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Hierarchy",
    "thirdOption": "Parish family",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Ten Commandments",
    "firstOption": "Cardinal and theological virtues",
    "question": "The “Decalogue” refers to?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Writings of the Church Fathers",
    "thirdOption": "Ten Commandments",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Six",
    "firstOption": "Four",
    "question": "It took this many years to complete the Catechism of the Catholic Church?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Six",
    "thirdOption": "Three",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Fathers",
    "firstOption": "Brothers",
    "question": "The pre eminent teachers and theologians of the early church are referred to as?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Fathers",
    "thirdOption": "Grandfathers",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Common work of the Trinity",
    "firstOption": "Parish finances",
    "question": " Divine economy refers to?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Common work of the Trinity",
    "thirdOption": "Tithing",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Perfumed oil used during baptism, confirmation and holy orders",
    "firstOption": " Incense used during funeral Masses",
    "question": "Chrism refers to?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Blessed oil used for anointing of the sick",
    "thirdOption": "Perfumed oil used during baptism, confirmation and holy orders",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Easter",
    "firstOption": "Easter",
    "question": "What is considered the “feast of feasts”?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Christmas",
    "thirdOption": "Good Friday",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Signet",
    "firstOption": "Signet",
    "question": "What is the name of the ring the Bishop wears?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Fisherman Ring",
    "thirdOption": "Apostle ring",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Honor your father and Mother.",
    "firstOption": "Don't kill",
    "question": "What is the fourth commandment?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Honor your father and Mother.",
    "thirdOption": "Don't commit adultery. ",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Purple",
    "firstOption": "Red and Yellow",
    "question": "What color of vestment does the priest wear during Lent or Advent?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Green",
    "thirdOption": "Purple",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Man",
    "firstOption": "Consubstantial",
    "question": "The English translation of the Catechism was held up for more than a year when some U.S. bishops objected to the use of which word?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Man",
    "thirdOption": "Concupiscence",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "St. Simon Stock",
    "firstOption": "St. Dominic",
    "question": "Who received the scapular from the Blessed virgin Mary?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "St. Simon Stock",
    "thirdOption": "St. Francis",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Abortion",
    "firstOption": "Euthanasia",
    "question": "The second edition of the English version of the Catechism was changed to reflect stronger language on this topic in light of Evangelium Vitae?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Death penalty",
    "thirdOption": "Abortion",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Revelation",
    "firstOption": "Gospel of John",
    "question": "Church teaching on a “heavenly liturgy” comes from?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Book of Isaiah",
    "thirdOption": "Revelation",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "St. Frances",
    "firstOption": "St. Frances",
    "question": "Which saint tamed a wild wolf?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "St. Christopher",
    "thirdOption": "St. Joseph",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Joseph",
    "firstOption": "Christ",
    "question": "Who is the Foster Father of Jesus?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Joseph",
    "thirdOption": "Mary",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Stole",
    "firstOption": "Armise",
    "question": "What is the name of the scald the priest wears on his neck during confession?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Stole",
    "thirdOption": "Chasable",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "French",
    "firstOption": "French",
    "question": "In which language was the current Catechism first published?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Italian",
    "thirdOption": "English",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Seventh — You shall not steal.",
    "firstOption": "Fifth — You shall not kill.",
    "question": "Respecting and caring for animals is taught as part of which commandment?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Seventh — You shall not steal.",
    "thirdOption": "Ninth — You shall not covet your neighbor’s goods.",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Three",
    "firstOption": "Three",
    "question": "How many persons are in the holy trinity?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Two",
    "thirdOption": "One",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Couples",
    "firstOption": "Bishop",
    "question": "Who is the chief celebrant of the sacrament of matrimony?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Priest",
    "thirdOption": "Couples",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Chasable",
    "firstOption": "Chasable",
    "question": "What is the name of the large coloured vestment the priest wears for mass?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Alb",
    "thirdOption": "Stole",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": " Come, O Lord.",
    "firstOption": " Why have you forsaken me?",
    "question": "“Marana tha” means?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": " Come, O Lord.",
    "thirdOption": "It is finished.",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "White and Yellow",
    "firstOption": "Red",
    "question": "What color are papal flags?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Purple",
    "thirdOption": "White and Yellow",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Baptism, Confirmation, Eucharist",
    "firstOption": "Baptism, Reconciliation, Eucharist",
    "question": "The Sacraments of Initiation are?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Baptism, Confirmation, Eucharist",
    "thirdOption": "Eucharist, Marriage, Holy Orders",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Argentina",
    "firstOption": "Uruguay",
    "question": "What country does pope Francis come from?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Italy",
    "thirdOption": "Argentina",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Rome",
    "firstOption": "Rome",
    "question": "Where did St. Peter die?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Jerusalem",
    "thirdOption": "Italy",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Martin Luther",
    "firstOption": "John Calvin",
    "question": "Some credit this person with producing the first Catechism text?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "John Smith",
    "thirdOption": "Martin Luther",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The sign of the cross",
    "firstOption": "The sign of the cross",
    "question": "Every prayer starts with?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "I believe",
    "thirdOption": "The creed",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Extraordinary time",
    "firstOption": "Extraordinary time",
    "question": "Which of these is not a liturgical season?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Ordinary time",
    "thirdOption": "Advent ",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Archangel",
    "firstOption": "Seraphim",
    "question": "Angel Gabriel is what type of Angel?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Cherubim",
    "thirdOption": "Archangel",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Red",
    "firstOption": "Red",
    "question": "What color of vestment does the priest wear on second of November?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Purple",
    "thirdOption": "Green",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Year D",
    "firstOption": "Year A",
    "question": "Which of these is not a liturgical year?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Year D",
    "thirdOption": "Year C",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "I believe",
    "firstOption": "Gloria",
    "question": "What do we call the summary of our Faith?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "I believe",
    "thirdOption": "Lord have mercy",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "6",
    "firstOption": "5",
    "question": "What is the maximum number of sacraments one can get?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "6",
    "thirdOption": "7",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "First",
    "firstOption": "First",
    "question": "Believing in superstitions like horoscopes, tarot cards and clairvoyants goes against this commandment?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Second",
    "thirdOption": "Third",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Mary",
    "firstOption": "Mary",
    "question": "To whom does the dogma of Immaculate Conception apply?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Joseph",
    "thirdOption": "Anne",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "A historical fact",
    "firstOption": "Wishful thinking",
    "question": "What is the nature of Jesus' resurrection?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "A historical fact",
    "thirdOption": "A ruse",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Repeating the name of Jesus" ,
    "firstOption": "Going to mass everyday",
    "question": "What is the simplest way of praying constantly?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Repeating the name of Jesus",
    "thirdOption": "praying the rosary",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "All of the above",
    "firstOption": "The prophets",
    "question": "Which part of the scriptures are fulfilled in Christ?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The law",
    "thirdOption": "All of the above",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The gospels",
    "firstOption": "The gospels",
    "question": "Which of this book is the heart of all scriptures?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The prophets",
    "thirdOption": "The book of wisdom",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Apostolic",
    "firstOption": "Apoplectic",
    "question": "The church is one, holy, catholic and, ________?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Apostolic",
    "thirdOption": "Apostolic",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Mary",
    "firstOption": "St John",
    "question": "The intercession of which Saint is sought most in the Rosary?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Mary",
    "thirdOption": "St Maria ",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "John Paul II",
    "firstOption": "John Paul I",
    "question": "Which of this popes canonised the greatest number of saints in his pontificate?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "John Paul II",
    "thirdOption": "pope Benedict the XVI",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The red sea",
    "firstOption": "The river Jordan",
    "question": "Which sea did Moses cross to escape from Egypt?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The red sea",
    "thirdOption": "The dead sea",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "No",
    "firstOption": "Yes,if it is fasting",
    "question": "Do catholics have to abstain from meat every friday of the year?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "No",
    "thirdOption": "Yes",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The Adhan",
    "firstOption": "Credo",
    "question": "Which of this is not a catholic prayer?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The Te Deum",
    "thirdOption": "The Adhan",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "All of the options",
    "firstOption": "Elijah",
    "question": "Which of these was an old Testament prophet?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "All of the options",
    "thirdOption": "Elisha",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Three",
    "firstOption": "Two",
    "question": "How many persons are there in the Trinity?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Three",
    "thirdOption": "One",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Joseph",
    "firstOption": "Jesus",
    "question": "To whom was Mary betrothed?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Joseph",
    "thirdOption": "Gabriel",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "St Paul",
    "firstOption": "St Paulo",
    "question": "Who wrote the first letter to the Thessalonians?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "St Paul",
    "thirdOption": "St Peter",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "St John the Apostle",
    "firstOption": "Saint John of the cross",
    "question": "Which Saint stayed at the foot of the cross during the crucifixion",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "St John the Apostle",
    "thirdOption": "John the fisher man",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The wars of Religion",
    "firstOption": "The wars of Christ",
    "question": "The wars fought in Europe over religious confession in the wake of the Reformation are called?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The Great wars",
    "thirdOption": "The wars of Religion",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Jesus Christ",
    "firstOption": "The Holy Spirit",
    "question": "Who for love died to save us and obtain forgiveness of sins?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Jesus Christ",
    "thirdOption": "The Angels ",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "One",
    "firstOption": "One",
    "question": "How many God(s)are there?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "An infinite number",
    "thirdOption": "Three",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "8",
    "firstOption": "3",
    "question": "For how many days does the Easter octave last?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "8",
    "thirdOption": "7",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Bishops",
    "firstOption": "Priests",
    "question": "Who are the successors of the Apostles?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Popes",
    "thirdOption": "All people",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Quo Vadis",
    "firstOption": "Quis es",
    "question": "In popular legeng what did St Peter say to Jesus as he was running away from Rome?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Quo Vadis",
    "thirdOption": "Qui Nobis",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "St Paul",
    "firstOption": "St James",
    "question": "which Saint wrote most of the Epistles(letters)in the New Testament?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "St Paul",
    "thirdOption": "St Peter",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Shamrock",
    "firstOption": "Shamrock",
    "question": "According to tradition,STPatrick used which plant to explain the Trinity?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Rose",
    "thirdOption": "Gum leaf",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Priory",
    "firstOption": "church",
    "question": "Which of these is not a Building set apart for liturgical worship?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Chapel",
    "thirdOption": "Priory",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Pilate",
    "firstOption": "Herod",
    "question": "Who was the Roman governor before whom Jesus appeared?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Pilate",
    "thirdOption": "Pharoh",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The of the father and of the son and of the holy spirit",
    "firstOption": "All of the above",
    "question": "The correct word to be used during the Rite of Baptism are'I baptise you in the name of_______?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The name of the creator, the redeemer. and the sanctifier",
    "thirdOption": "The of the father and of the son and of the holy spirit",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "St Joseph",
    "firstOption": "St James",
    "question": "Which saint is the city San Jose named after?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "St Joseph",
    "thirdOption": "St Peters",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Hail Mary",
    "firstOption": "Hail Mary",
    "question": "Which prayer begins in Latin 'AVE MARIA?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Holy Mary",
    "thirdOption": "Our Father",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Sixth",
    "firstOption": "fourth",
    "question": "Which commandment encompasses the whole of human sexuality?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "fifth",
    "thirdOption": "Sixth",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Modesty",
    "firstOption": "Modesty",
    "question": "Which virtue assists one to refuse to unveil what should remain hidden?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Truth",
    "thirdOption": "Temperance",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "It is Everlasting",
    "firstOption": "Until the judgement day",
    "question": "How will God's love last?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "It is Everlasting",
    "thirdOption": "Until death",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Alone",
    "firstOption": "Alone",
    "question": "The word of God says that is not good for a man to __________?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Too busy",
    "thirdOption": "Rich",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Interior conversion",
    "firstOption": "Fasting",
    "question": "Which of these type of conversion is the most important?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Interior conversion",
    "thirdOption": "Mortification",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The church",
    "firstOption": "The church",
    "question": "The sacrament of Matrimony signifies the union between Christ and______ ?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The world",
    "thirdOption": "The Trinity",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "40",
    "firstOption": "30",
    "question": "How many days did Jesus stayed in the desert after his baptism?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "40",
    "thirdOption": "3",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Ordination of priest",
    "firstOption": "Rite of religious profession",
    "question": "Which of these is a sacrament?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Consecration of a virgin",
    "thirdOption": "Ordination of priest",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The finding of Jesus in the Temple",
    "firstOption": "The crossing of the red sea",
    "question": "Which event breaks the silence of the Gospels about the hidden years of Jesus?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The finding of Jesus in the Temple",
    "thirdOption": "The multiplication of the loaves",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Obedience",
    "firstOption": "Obedience",
    "question": "The Evangelical counsels are: poverty, chastity, and __________?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Love",
    "thirdOption": "Hope",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Justification",
    "firstOption": "All of the above",
    "question": "What detaches from sin ,purifies the heart brings about reconciliation with God and heals?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Yoga",
    "thirdOption": "Justification",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The most Holy Trinity",
    "firstOption": "The tabernacle",
    "question": "What is the central mystery of christian faith and life?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The most Holy Trinity",
    "thirdOption": "The vatican Bank",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "We must forgive others",
    "firstOption": "We must love God",
    "question": "What condition is given to our father that must be met to obtain forgiveness?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "We must forgive others",
    "thirdOption": "We must not sin",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "All people",
    "firstOption": "All people",
    "question": "Who is called to enter the Messianic kingdom?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "christians",
    "thirdOption": "Muslims",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Hell",
    "firstOption": "Heaven",
    "question": "Where do people go after death who died in mortal sin without repenting and accepting Gods merciful love?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Hell",
    "thirdOption": "Purgatory",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "First",
    "firstOption": "First",
    "question": "Atheism is a sin against which commandment?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Second",
    "thirdOption": "Fourth",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Futile",
    "firstOption": "Beneficial",
    "question": "The Catechism teaches that any attempt to ignore sin or to give this dark reality other names would be?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Futile",
    "thirdOption": "Bad",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Almsgiving",
    "firstOption": "Speaking in tongues",
    "question": "The three main forms of interior penance of the Christian are fasting, prayer and _____________?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Flaggelation",
    "thirdOption": "Almsgiving",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Despair",
    "firstOption": "Despair",
    "question": "What is it called when someone ceases to hope for personal salvation from God and for the forgiveness of sins?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Presumption",
    "thirdOption": "Apostacy",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "St. Peter",
    "firstOption": "Martin Luther",
    "question": "Who did Jesus make the rock of the Church?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "St. Andrew",
    "thirdOption": "St. Peter",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Jesus Christ",
    "firstOption": "Isaiah",
    "question": "In whom does the old Covenant prefiguring find their fulfilment?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Jesus Christ",
    "thirdOption": "Mary",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Proclaiming Jesus to lead others to Faith in him",
    "firstOption": "Proclaiming Jesus to lead others to Faith in him",
    "question": "In what does the transmission of the Christian Faith primarily consist?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Works of social justice",
    "thirdOption": "Building of churches",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Old",
    "firstOption": "Old",
    "question": "In the sacramental economy the Holy Spirit fulfils what was prefigured in the ___________ covenant?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "New",
    "thirdOption": "Ark of the",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The altar",
    "firstOption": "The baptismal font",
    "question": "To which part of the church do spiritual authors sometimes compare the heart that prays?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The pew",
    "thirdOption": "The altar",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Bishops",
    "firstOption": "The Archbishops",
    "question": "Who validly ordains the three degrees of the sacrament of Holy Orders (deacons, Priests and Bishops)?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Bishops",
    "thirdOption": "The Pope",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "All People",
    "firstOption": "All People",
    "question": "Who is called to enter the messianic kingdom?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Christians",
    "thirdOption": "Catholics",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Do good and avoid evil",
    "firstOption": "Do good and avoid evil",
    "question": "What does the moral law urge us to do?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Do evil and avoid good",
    "thirdOption": "Pray and fast",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Sunday",
    "firstOption": "Saturday",
    "question": "On which day of the week does the church oblige the faithful to go to mass?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Monday",
    "thirdOption": "Sunday",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "There will your heart be also",
    "firstOption": "Do not tell anyone",
    "question": "Finish this Gospel saying: Where your treasure is _______?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "There will your heart be also",
    "thirdOption": "God knows",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Anointing of the sick",
    "firstOption": "Anointing of the sick",
    "question": "Which sacrament is especially intended to strengthen those who are being tried by illness?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Holy Orders",
    "thirdOption": "Confirmation",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Francisco Franco",
    "firstOption": "Francisco Franco",
    "question": "In the Spanish civil war, who led the side with which most catholics were allied?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Martin Luther",
    "thirdOption": "Benito Mussolini",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Our Lady Help of Christians",
    "firstOption": "St. Alphege the Bald",
    "question": "Who is one of the patron saints of Australia?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Our Lady Help of Christians",
    "thirdOption": "St. Alphonsus",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "15th",
    "firstOption": "14th",
    "question": "In which century did the Reformation begin?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "16th",
    "thirdOption": "15th",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The grace of the Lord be with all. Amen",
    "firstOption": "The grace of the Lord be with all. Amen",
    "question": "What are the last words of the Bible?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "In the beginning",
    "thirdOption": "Now start again",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The Red Sea",
    "firstOption": "The Red Sea",
    "question": "Which sea did Moses cross to escape from Egypt?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The Dead sea",
    "thirdOption": "The Ageaen sea",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Archangel",
    "firstOption": "Cherub",
    "question": "St. Micheal is what type of angel?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Archangel",
    "thirdOption": "Seraph",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The sign of Peace",
    "firstOption": "The Wail",
    "question": "Which of these may take place during the mass, shortly after the Our Father?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The trumpet call",
    "thirdOption": "The sign of Peace",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Mammon",
    "firstOption": "Mammon",
    "question": "What did Jesus say, you cannot serve God and?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Mammal",
    "thirdOption": "Mommon",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Joseph",
    "firstOption": "Zachariah",
    "question": "To whom was Mary Betrothed?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Joseph",
    "thirdOption": "Ahab",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The Reformation",
    "firstOption": "The Protest",
    "question": "What is the name of the event when large numbers of people broke communion with Rome in protest against perceived abuses by members of the Catholic Heirarchy?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The Restoration",
    "thirdOption": "The Reformation",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The sea of Galilee",
    "firstOption": "The Sea of the Dead",
    "question": "What sea did Jesus walk on?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The Red sea",
    "thirdOption": "The sea of Galilee",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "indissoluble",
    "firstOption": "indissoluble",
    "question": "The matrimonial union of man and woman in the sacrament of Holy Matrimony is ________?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "absolved",
    "thirdOption": "irrevocable",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Alone",
    "firstOption": "Free",
    "question": "The Word of God says that its not good that man should be ________?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Alone",
    "thirdOption": "Rich",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Free gift",
    "firstOption": "Option",
    "question": "Faith is a _______ given by God?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Free gift",
    "thirdOption": "Earned gift",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Three: Seven",
    "firstOption": "One: nine",
    "question": "In the Ten commandments, what is the ratio between those which concern love of God and those which concern love of neighbour?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Five: Five",
    "thirdOption": "Three: Seven",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "His love and goodness",
    "firstOption": "His love and goodness",
    "question": "What was God's reason for creating?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "His power",
    "thirdOption": "His loneliness",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "A saint who is chosen as a protector or guardian",
    "firstOption": "A saint who looks after customers",
    "question": "What is a patron saint?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "A saint one prays for money",
    "thirdOption": "A saint who is chosen as a protector or guardian",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The Wars of Religion",
    "firstOption": "The Death wars",
    "question": "The wars fought in Europe over religious confession in the wake of the Reformation are called?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The Great wars",
    "thirdOption": "The Wars of Religion",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The Black Death",
    "firstOption": "The Black Death",
    "question": "The phenomenon which decimated Christian Europe in the 14th century was called?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The red Death",
    "thirdOption": "The Spanish flu",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "The catacomb of Priscilla, Rome",
    "firstOption": "St. Francis Xavier Cathedral, Adelaide",
    "question": "The earliest paintings of Mary with Jesus are found where?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The catacomb of Priscilla, Rome",
    "thirdOption": "St. John, Cathedral",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Michealangelo",
    "firstOption": "St. Sixtus",
    "question": "Which artist painted the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Cario Granto",
    "thirdOption": "Michealangelo",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Divine Wisdom",
    "firstOption": "Divine Wisdom",
    "question": "The moral law is the work of _______?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "The Government",
    "thirdOption": "Chance",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "St. Peter",
    "firstOption": "St. Paul",
    "question": "Which saint cut off the ear of one of the soldiers arresting Jesus?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "St. Peter",
    "thirdOption": "St. John",
    "timer": 20
  },
  {
    "correctOption": "Shamrock",
    "firstOption": "Gum leaf",
    "question": "According to tradition, St. Patrick used which plant to explain the Trinity?",
    "quiz": "Catholic Faith",
    "secondOption": "Fig",
    "thirdOption": "Shamrock",
    "timer": 20
  }
]